Nguyễn Quang Thành

System Administrator, Network Engineer, Security Engineer







29/08/1989

150 Hoa Dao, Ward 2, Phu Nhuan District, Ho Chi Minh City, TP Hô Chí I'm Thanh Nguyen, an IT professional with many years of experience in the field. With logical and creative thinking, I always find effective solutions to complex technical problems. I am capable of working both in teams and independently. Professionalism and responsibility are my guiding principles in all the work I have undertaken. I believe that with my qualities and skills, I will contribute positively to the development of the team and the project.



EDUCATION

Hanoi University of Industry

08/2008 - 06/2012

Computer Science

SKILL

Excellent

Networking	Cloud
Linux	AWS
Docker	Kubernetes

Intermediate

MySQL	MongoDB
,	

CERTIFICATE

From Code to Production with VMware Tanzu

10/2023

VMware LEARNING

LFS169 - Introduction to GitOps

10/2023

The Linux Foundation

LFC108 Cybersecurity Essentials

10/2023

The Linux Foundation

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/2022 - Now

IT TEAMLEADER I DANH KHOI REAL ESTATE SERVICES JOINT STOCK COMPANY

- Manage the IT Team: Assign tasks, supervise, and evaluate the performance of team members. Build and maintain a positive work environment, encouraging creativity and teamwork.
- Manage Network Infrastructure: Design, deploy, and maintain LAN, WAN, and WIRELESS network infrastructure based on devices such as Cisco, Peplink, Fortinet.
- Manage Server and Storage Systems: Install, configure, and maintain Windows and Linux servers, virtualization systems such as VMware Vsphere. Manage SAN storage systems, ensuring data safety and security.
- IT Project Management: Plan, implement, and oversee IT projects, ensuring completion on time and within budget. Interact with other departments to understand technology needs and propose appropriate solutions.
- Developing and Implementing IT Policies: Draft and enforce policies, procedures, and regulations related to IT infrastructure management.

04/2018 - 08/2022

IT System Administrator | ISOFH MEDTECH COMPANY - IVI **GROUP**

- Manage, deploy and maintain Jenkins CICD cycles of HIS / EMR applications for 25 projects of big hospitals and clinics on-premise infrastructureLAN - WAN Network infrastructure based on network devices: Cisco, Peplink, Fortinet, HP Aruba,...
- Manage, deploy and maintain Jenkins CICD pipelines of pharmacy store system web application as well as Medical appointment booking mobile application of Isofhcare on AWS platform
- Deploy, maintain and manage IVI token coin on Cloud platform such as AWS and Sunteco (include Al chatbot applications, exchange services on BSC scan platform), support developer on deploying application using Jenkins

Fortinet FortiGate 7.4 Operator

10/2023

Fortinet

Fortinet Certified Associate Cybersecurity

10/2023

Fortinet

CCNA Routing and Switching

10/2013

CISCO

and GilabCl flow

- Manage and operate internal window server 2016 domain controller,
 Active Directory and upgrade to Windows server 2019 and company's DNS management
- Manage and operate internal company's VMware Esxi and Vcenter
- Setup, manage and write configuration code for Prometheus monitoring system in order that Team can be able to monitor around 400+ servers,1000+ services, visualize whole internal infrastructure using Grafana dashboard, send alerts to Telegram and Email
- Setup and write documents to guide Hospital's IT office to self-visualize own infrastructure using Prometheus & Grafana, Zabbix
- Implement CD flows using Gitlab / Ansible for managing and deploying applications, using ansible in order to deploy new config for nginx, haproxy, install new database for new server such as postgresql master - slave, mysql
- Setup, operate, manage and implement configuration for load balancers such as HAproxy, Nginx
- Tunning, Hardening OS (ubuntu, centos), customize configuration of services such as (redis, rabbitmq, postgresql, nginx, haproxy), operate and manage Jira, Confluence, Gitlab server, NAS. Troubleshoot Jenkins's job build on failure while deploying application code
- Manage and Restrict user's access through Guacamole server
- Deploy and Setup a solution for gathering application logs, centralize and visualize using Grafana Loki, Elasticsearch & Kibana
- Implement His/Emr on K8s staging cluster, logging on cluster using ELK, develop CI/CD on gitops platform (ArgoCD, GitlabCl, Harbor registry)
- Suggest and Consult Cloud infrastructure solutions for hospital or clinic in needs
- Offer data backup solution from third-party vendor using Veeam to store on-premise or transfer backup version onto AWS S3

10/2013 - 07/2017

IT Administrator I VNC POLYESTER FIBER CO.,LTD

- Main responsibilities: Management and Operation
- LAN WAN WIRELESS Network infrastructure based on network devices: Cisco, Peplink, Fortinet, HP Aruba,...
- Install, upgrade, support and troubleshoot Windows 7 and 8, 10, 11, Microsoft Office 365 and any other authorized desktop applications
- Firewall devices: Fortigate, Pfsense
- P2P, MPLS, FTTH, ILL lines and data transmission connections between branch offices. Head Offices and Data Center.
- Virtual private network (VPN) connections between branch offices,
 Head Offices, Data Center and Clients' Remote Access connections to Data
 Center
- Virtual Server system: Vmware Vsphere 7.0
- Storage System include: SAN and NAS
- Design, Implement, Migration and Troubleshoot network infrastructure of branch offices, Head Offices and Data Center.
- Manage and coordinate the work of IT Infrastructure team
- Drafting policies on Infrastructure operation for company
- Support Application Team and partners to deploy Applications for the company

08/2012 - 10/2013

IT Staff | ROYAL INTERNATIONNAL CORPORTION

- Server system administration 2008 2012: DC server, ISA server, mail server
- Configure Draytek devices, telephone exchange, setup the network

- Manage office computer systems
- Troubleshoot hardware, software, computer networks, cameras, access control, security control
- Knowledge of some business management software
- Managing the use of IT-related office equipment
- Organize the authorization of access to use, backup, ensure the safety and security of data and data on the system
- Support users with problems on LAN, Internet, software, printers, install software according to user requirements and other problems that may occur when using computers
- Periodically check and maintain computer equipment, printers and other equipment; Proposing to buy new, upgrade computer quipment for working in departments
- Provide solutions to make the Company's activities more efficient, accurate and secure